SAMYUKTA MUDUGAL

1540 Meachum Way Erie, CO 80516

ABOUT ME

I have spent 5+ years in the embedded world writing code in C, C++, Python and Assembly quickly learning numerous storage protocols along the way. Working in the Storage Industry, I had to engineer firmware to interface with many different hardware components. I learnt a lot while writing code for a high performant, memory constrained system towards an innovative technology. I would love to broaden my skill set by working in an innovative industry.

SKILLS

Skills C, C++, Python, Assembly Language Programming, ARM, RTOS

Certifications Certified Scrum Master, CU Embedded Systems Certification

Source Control SVN, Git

Storage Protocols NVMe, AHCI, SAS, SATA

Protocol Test Tools Lauterbach Debugger, JDSU - SAS jammer, SAS Analyzer, LeCroy – PCIe Analyzer,

Drive Master

WORK EXPERIENCE

Staff Firmware Engineer

SanDisk, a WD Brand Feb 2016 – Current

- o Wrote unit tests in a **Python**
- Below are details of my work on firmware for Enterprise NVMe SSD
 - Worked on chip bring-up and hardware check-out of the ARM controller.
 Implemented low level code in Assembly and C to interact with the HW.
 - Designed and implemented features like end-to-end data path protection,
 Security, PCI ereset functionality, error recovery and various NVMe protocol specific features.
 - Worked on code for various HW components like SPI, UART, DMA engines, HW interrupts, Encryption engine, Inter Processor Communication.
 - Very proficient with the use of debuggers and analyzers.
 - Implemented various tasks that run within a RTOS.
 - Worked seamlessly with QA and manufacturing teams to fix bugs and strengthen the product.

Senior Firmware Engineer

SanDisk, a WD Brand April 2013 – Feb 2016

- Developed features for PCIe based AHCI SSDs such as AHCI BAR space initialization, PCIe Error Recovery, PCIe Core and PCIe DMA module.
- Analyzed customer specifications vs. industry standards and scheduled feature implementations.
- o Implemented interface code, features and bug fixes for SATA and SAS SSD.

Firmware Development Engineer

LSI Corporation
May 2011 – April 2013

- Developed firmware for SAS3 RAID HBA. This involves the understanding and implementation of RAID types 0, 1, 10, 5 in C++.
- o Worked on improving the I/O performance of the SAS3 HBA. This involved in depth analysis of the code, IO path and maximising the efficiency of the IO path.
- Worked in Systems Engineering for 6 months. This involved direct interaction with customers, debugging customer reported issues and forming a reliable interface between the customers and the developers.
- o Prototyped the use of a static analysis tool called Coverity.

R&D Intern

Covidien Energy Based Devices May 2010 – April 2011

- Built a UI to interface with a DSP Control Board using the Serial Interface (RS232).
- o Interfaced an analog to digital Impedance Converter Board to a DSP Control Board using the I2C interface.
- Built a C#, .NET based GUI to provide extensive control to the DSP Control Board.

EDUCATION

Graduate M.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering 2009 - 2011

2005 - 2009

University of Colorado, Boulder

GPA: 3.8

Undergraduate B.E. in Electronics and Communication

Visveswaraiah Technological University, India

GPA: 3.9 (Aggregate: 82%)

NOTEWORTHY MENTIONS

o Presentlyvolunteering as a TA for **STEM related workshops** such as Scratch, Sphero, Python, Electronic Circuits, and Arduino for kids at the **Lafayette Public Library**. Organized by the Lafayette Tech Meetup group.

- o Volunteered as a **tech consultant** at **Imagine Smart Home** in Boulder. Helped the disabled residents use various tech devices.
- o Volunteered at the Children's Literacy Center at Colorado Springs. Helped kids with reading.
- o Volunteered for the **Expand Your Horizon Conference** held in CU. It's a conference for middle school girls to expose them to the world of Science, Math, Engineering and Technology.